Yin Shen

phone: 13661412926 email: shenyin@rocketmail.com

Self-assessment

Have been working for more than ten years and building up extensive and abundant experience in application software development. Through continuous hard working and studying, I am able to handle difficult work independently, write high quality design document and fix bug carefully without regression. I have excellent teamwork spirit and communication skills as I work well with a multicultural and diverse work force. Furthermore, I am skillful in setting up a team, and have great leadership and executive ability.

Specialties

- Have experience with C++, C#, Java, SQL and Javascript.
- Web experience : Vue, Vuex, Electron
- Node.js expert
- Use Xamarin to develop mobile applications (Android and iOS)
- Server side experience: Spring Cloud, Spring Boot, Koa2

Work Experience

OnChain, Software Architect, 2018/7/1 - 2019/7/31

Design both server side and client side system based on the blockchain. I lead and design these programs and documents:

- 1. ONTO: a blockchain wallet:
- 2. Blockchain Explorer: show informations in the blockchain;
- 3. OnChain Custodian: a digital assets custodial platform;
- 4. DDXF: a data exchange system base on blockchain;
- 5. refine web api by restful style.

These programs use java, objc, spring boot, mysql, elastic search, kafka, etc.

Alibaba - Banma, Technical Expert, 2016/4 – 2018/7/1

I build an agile software development team which has 20 workmates to develop apps in cars. We create the first internet car of the world whose name is Roewe RX5. You can find details at website http://www.roewe.com.cn

My team develop these programs:

- 1. self-driving traveling app;
- 2. motorcade-forming app, by which members can see everybody on the map;
- 3. connect a car with IOT devices such as drone, automobile data recorder air cleaner, etc.

We use node is and cpp to develop apps.

Reliable, CoFounder & CTO, 2014/11 - 2016/4

I lead team to develop mobile applications and web site to accomplish our business strategy. We complete mobile applications on both Android and iOS platforms and three websites within half a year.

You can find the company information here: http://www.mreliable.com/pages/index.html. This company land on NEEQ concept stock.

Use Xamarin to build Android and iOS app; Vue to build website; Service Stack to build server.

Baidu, Senior Developer, 2014/04 – 2014/11

I focus on developing web browser. I decrease crash rate from 3% to 0.3% by refactoring smart pointer in animation engine, so that our product is released successfully.

Use windbg to analyze dump file, cpp, javascript.

SAP, Developer, 2011/06 - 2014/4

Deliver business logic enhancement and innovation to customers in small business segment. Take tasks in the full product development life cycle, such as spec comprehension, design, coding, testing and bug fixing.

Communicate and collaborate with global product management, development and QA team around the world to fulfill the requirements in time.

I participate two programs:

1. business one: a C/S ERP software for small company.

2. business anywhere: a B/S ERP Could system.

Use java, cpp, javascript, h5

Beyond-soft, Senior Developer, 2010/08 - 2011/06

Fix bugs of Visual Studio 2012. Visual Studio is an integrated development environment (IDE) from Microsoft. This job requires many debugging skills and good communication skills. Debug on remote machine and resolve customer's issues.

Use C#, cpp.

KEDACOM, Developer, 2008/08 - 2010/08

Develop NVR (Network Video Recorder) system. I make our product be state of the art, and have good usability and scalability.

Use cpp in program.

Education

Northwest University (China) 2004/09 -- 2008/07

Bachelor, Computer Science and Technology

Reference

Write some programs in my leisure:

- 1. Lisp runtime written by javascript: https://github.com/benhaben/mylisp
- 2. Chemistry graph search: https://github.com/benhaben/chembing, you can use it at http://www.molbase.com/en/search/index.htm
- 3. A website to practice Koa2 and Vue: http://tokafun.com

4. WeChat mini program: "好运码头"

Write some technical blogs :

- 1. javascript v8 engine: https://www.jianshu.com/p/6373de1e117d
- 2. Neo(blockchain system) compiler and vm: https://www.jianshu.com/p/6461b4e18089